raymondjames.com 2001-02-04

# Raymond James Financial - Internet Privacy Statement for www.raymondjames.com

Raymond James Financial is committed to online privacy.

Visitors may browse the Raymond James Web site to learn about our many services, get delayed quotes and find career opportunities without giving any personal information. Any information collected on this site, i.e. the zip code entered for the Office Locator system is used only to locate the closest Raymond James offices and is not kept in any format. Personal information is only made available when a site visitor volunteers it, through our Contact Us page, to request that a Raymond James Financial Advisor contact them. This information is sent to the Financial Advisor through e-mail and is not collected in any other format.

Web site visitor information with respect to non-clients __ is collected with the use of computer IP addresses on an aggregate, anonymous basis in which no personal information is associated with this data. This data is gathered through the use of Web server log files where site activity is stored. The information is used to help diagnose problems with our server, to measure the use of our Web site content and to administer our Web site. None of the information gathered by the Web server is associated with you as an individual. Although this contains no personal information other than the IP address, it may be used to track down an individual who is attacking or misusing our resources. Cookie files are used on the site to help visitors navigate the site more easily.

We do store information regarding actions taken by clients when they access their client accounts. This information may be provided to the client's Financial Advisor and to other Raymond James Associates who provide services or products to the client.

Raymond James offers online services via OnlinePlus to a limited segment of its client base. To protect our client information, users are required to log in using a unique user name and password. Raymond James uses encryption technology to secure client data as it is being transferred between computers and also has implemented a combination of computer hardware and software to keep unauthorized users from accessing information on Raymond James' computer network.

This site contains links to other Web sites. www.RaymondJames.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

The Raymond James Internet Privacy Statement applies to U.S. clients and Web site visitors only.

Raymond James Financial may change this privacy statement at any time. Any changes or updates will be effective immediately upon posting to this site.

### PRIVACY NOTICE TO RAYMOND JAMES CLIENTS

Raymond James is committed to protecting confidentiality of the information furnished to us by our clients. We are providing you this information as required by Regulation S-P adopted by the Securities and Exchange Commission.

We collect nonpublic personal information about clients from the following sources:

  * Information we receive from them on applications or other forms;
  * Information about their transactions with us, our affiliates or others; and
  * Information we may receive from a consumer-reporting agency.

#### Our Use of Information About Clients

We may share information about clients with other companies in the Raymond James family (that is, companies that are owned by Raymond James Financial, Inc., our parent company). Otherwise, unless a client has consented or directed us to do so, we do not disclose any nonpublic personal information about the client to anyone except as permitted by law. We follow the same policy with respect to nonpublic information received from all clients and former clients.

#### How We Protect Client Confidential Information

Raymond James has policies that restrict access to nonpublic personal information about clients to those employees who have need for that information to provide investment alternatives or services to those clients, or to employees who assist those who provide investment alternatives or services to them. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect their nonpublic personal information.

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site or your dealings with this Web site, please contact me.

Thank you,

_Lawrence Silver

Marketing Director  
Raymond James Financial  
880 Carillon Parkway  
St. Petersburg, FL 33716  

_
